### **Tomas Madariaga**

1311 Bonita Ave 94709 Berkeley CA +1 510 338 2169

www.tomasmadariaga.com - es.linkedin.com/in/tomasmadariaga/en - www.github.com/tomasmax madariaga.tomas@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack developer, IT consultant, worked in Start-ups & Big B2B consulting company. Agile Project Management MSc. Big Thinker, Lifelong Learner, Entrepreneur, Business & Result oriented. Willing to create new prototypes & solutions. Enthusiastic about improving my skills in Project & Product Management, Software Engineering, Innovation and Business.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Developer & Product Manager, San Francisco, Moovit

August 2016 - Present

Front end developer (HTML5, JavaScript, AWS). Work with UX/UI teams to bring wireframes, design to life. Serve as product manager to translate partner needs into development requirements. App & Web prototyping with <a href="mailto:proto.io">proto.io</a>

#### Full Stack Developer & Consultant, Spain, Indra

January 2015 - July 2016

Consultancy and development of an Android <u>smart mobility solution</u> to speed up maintenance of several utility companies network. ESRI GIS back end with JBOSS serve. Mobile Android, Desk & Web .NET dev. B2B Mobile consulting.

Freelance Project Management Coach, Bilbao, Fondo Formacion Euskadi

May – July 2015

 $\label{lem:condition} \textbf{Created a MOOC to increase some Coworking Space Managers Project Management efficiency, \underline{\textbf{PIRECOW}}\ project.}$ 

Project Manager & Software Engineer, RoR, HTML5, Phonegap. Bilbao, <u>Grupo Urbegi</u> February 2013 – December 2014

Managed & developed <u>Council of Bizkaia's loan requests</u> filtering web service, allowing to reduce their response time, RoR.

Development of a <u>Crowdfunding platform</u>. Mediapost Group rebranding consultancy, <u>websites</u> design, development & SEO.

#### Freelance Web Developer & Designer & Marketing

September – December 2013

Connect already developed online game with Facebook. Designed advertisements and marketing strategies to introduce a new IT product in the Spanish market.

Software Engineer Intern - Ruby on Rails, Java, Bilbao, Techabout

Advanced Project Management Postgraduate Degree, University of Barcelona

October 2011 - July 2012

Meetabout entrepreneurial project web development (back & front end) Ruby on Rails and Java OSGi.

#### **EDUCATION**

naturated in open management i obligational beginning of barrensity	
PMBOK, PMP, Prince2, Lean Project Management, Six Sigma. Agile methodologies: Agile, Scrum	
MSE in Industrial Engineering (Business Management), GPA: 3.5, U. of Deusto	2010 – 2013
MSE in Business Engineering, (Erasmus), Solvay Brussels School, Brussels, Belgium	2012 – 2013
MSE in Computer Science, GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto, Bilbao	2010 – 2013
BSc in Computer Science, GPA: 3.2 University of Deusto, Bilbao	2007 – 2010

## COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

<u>Machine Learning Specialization</u>, University of Washington, Coursera Big Data Specialization, University of San Diego, Coursera 2016

2014

Lean IT Foundation Certification, APMG International

2016 2015

2014

<u>Programming Mobile Services for Android Handheld Systems: Concurrency</u> by Vanderbilt University on Coursera <u>Programming Mobile Applications for Android Handheld Systems</u>, University of Maryland, College Park on Coursera <u>Bizkaia Talentia Program</u>, Selected because of my skills and academic record.

Software Engineering for Software as a Service, University of California, Berkeley, Coursera

2012

Ingenio: Innovation, Creativity and Entrepreneurship Program, University of Deusto, Bilbao

2011

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Java, C/C++, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, SASS, LESS, CSS3, AngularJS, EmberJS, Bootstrap, SEO. Android and Cordova (Phonegap). MVC architecture. Professional experience in Back-end, Front-end, AWS and Heroku. Proficient with GIT and SVN. TDD. SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS DB. AWS Big Data, Tableau, Pentaho and Rapidminer.

# ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE & AWARDS

Coursera's Global Translator Community (GTC) Volunteer, translate subtitles for course lecture videos.

Ironhack program Ambassador at the University of Deusto, helping founders to publicize it in Bilbao.

Physics and mathematics Private teacher

2013 – 2015

University of Deusto Business IX Forum Employment and Entrepreneurship Business Simulator winner.

2013 – 2015